{
    "topic": "Fundamentals of Data Communication",
    "Subject": "Computer Networks",
    "data": [
        {
            "question": "A digital channel implies that the channel",
            "op1": "is digitized",
            "op2": "is carrying digital data",
            "op3": "is without carrier",
            "op4": "none of these above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Twisting of wire reduces",
            "op1": "interference",
            "op2": "impulse noise",
            "op3": "low frequency interference",
            "op4": "none of these above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following transmission is concerned with content of the data ?",
            "op1": "nalog transmission",
            "op2": "Digital transmission",
            "op3": "Both analog and digital transmission",
            "op4": "None of these above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following medium does not use metallic conductor for transmission ?",
            "op1": "Twisted pair",
            "op2": "Coaxial cable",
            "op3": "Optical fiber",
            "op4": "None of these above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Dual cable and signal cable are the two types of",
            "op1": "Broadband networks",
            "op2": "Radio networks",
            "op3": "Baseband networks",
            "op4": "Satellite networks",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Light is confined within the core of a simple optical fiber by ________",
            "op1": "Refraction",
            "op2": "Reflection from the fiber\u2019s plastic coating",
            "op3": "Total internal reflection at the core cladding boundary",
            "op4": "Total internal reflection at the outer edge of the cladding",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the following communications channels, which does not provide a physical link between terminal and the computer ?",
            "op1": "Optical fiber",
            "op2": "Telephone line",
            "op3": "oaxial cable",
            "op4": "Microwave",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The highest data rate is provided by the transmission medium",
            "op1": "Microwave",
            "op2": "Twisted pairs",
            "op3": "Optical fiber",
            "op4": "Coaxial cable",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Computer in a computer network are connected by",
            "op1": "Satellite channel only",
            "op2": "Telephone line only",
            "op3": "Either telephone line or satellite channel",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "In ______ transmission, a start bit and stop bit from a character byte.",
            "op1": "Parallel",
            "op2": "Asynchronous",
            "op3": "Synchronous",
            "op4": "ata transfer",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Communication system is a combination of",
            "op1": "Hardware",
            "op2": "Software",
            "op3": "Data transfer links",
            "op4": "All of the above",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The slowest transmission speeds are those of",
            "op1": "Coaxial cable",
            "op2": "Twisted pair wire",
            "op3": "Fiber-optic cable",
            "op4": "Microwave",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Fiber optic communication system uses:",
            "op1": "Simplex communication",
            "op2": "Full-duplex",
            "op3": "Both (A) and (B)",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Transmission media are usually categorized as",
            "op1": "Determinate and indeterminate",
            "op2": "Guided or unguided",
            "op3": "Fixed or unfixed",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which transmission mode is used for data communication along telephone line ?",
            "op1": "Parallel",
            "op2": "Asynchronous",
            "op3": "Synchronous",
            "op4": "Serial",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "In fiber optic, the signal source is",
            "op1": "Light",
            "op2": "Radio",
            "op3": "Very low frequency",
            "op4": "Microwave frequency",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a guided medium ?",
            "op1": "Coaxial cable",
            "op2": "Twisted pair wire",
            "op3": "Fiber-optic cable",
            "op4": "Atmosphere",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The inner core of an optical fiber is ______",
            "op1": "Copper",
            "op2": "Glass or plastic",
            "op3": "Liquid",
            "op4": "Bimetallic",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Coaxial cables are widely used in",
            "op1": "Cable TV networks",
            "op2": "Telephone networks",
            "op3": "Both (A) and (B)",
            "op4": "Computer networks",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a voiceband channel ?",
            "op1": "Telephone line",
            "op2": "Coaxial cable",
            "op3": "Microwave systems",
            "op4": "Telegraph line",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a transmission medium ?",
            "op1": "Microwave systems",
            "op2": "Telephone lines",
            "op3": "oaxial cable",
            "op4": "Modem",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "Coaxial cable has conductors with",
            "op1": "Equal resistance",
            "op2": "The same diameter",
            "op3": "(A) and (B) both",
            "op4": "A common axis",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The following medium does not use metallic conductor for transmission",
            "op1": "Coaxial cable",
            "op2": "Optical fiber",
            "op3": "Twisted pair",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the device that connect two computers by means of a telephone line ?",
            "op1": "Cable",
            "op2": "us",
            "op3": "Modem",
            "op4": "Tape",
            "answer:": 3
        }
    ]
}